# **Anjitesh Shandilya**

LinkedIn- linkedin.com/in/ianjiteshan Github- github.com/ianjiteshan

Anjitesh Shandilya, a Bachelor of Technology student at the University School of Information, Communication and Technology, specializes in web development, full-stack development, machine learning, and Al. Combining strong technical expertise with excellent time management and organizational skills, he is well-equipped to tackle challenges and excel in dynamic, tech-driven environments

#### **EDUCATION**

. University School of Information, Communication and Technology

Bachelor of Technology - Information Technology

Kendriya Vidyalaya Vikaspuri 12th CBSE- 93 %

Delhi International School, Dwarka Sec23 10th CBSE - 93 %

Delhi, India

November 2022 - Present

New Delhi

April 2020 - March 2022

New Delhi

April 2007 - March 2020

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- Languages: C, C++, Ruby, JavaScript, Java, Python, MATLAB
- Frameworks: ReactJS, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, Django, Flask, Spring Boot, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, SQL, MS Access, Firebase
- AI/ML Tools & Technologies: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Keras, OpenCV, NLTK, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Adaptability, Event Management, Time Management
- Other Skills: Frontend Responsive Design, Backend, APIs, MERN Web Development, AI/ML Enthusiast, AWS, CAD

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## AI ML Intern, IBM-CSRbox

July 2024-August 2024

Email: anjitesh1976@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9310666586

- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to implement data-driven algorithms and models using Python, enhancing the accuracy of machine learning systems.
- Developed software solutions to address business challenges by applying data structures and algorithms, resulting in increased efficiency in predictive analytics tasks.
- · Participated in code reviews and debugged existing modules to optimize ML workflows, improving overall system performance.
- Implemented preventive maintenance strategies, resulting in a 20% decrease in downtime.

# Web Development Intern, NexusLogic Technologies

Sep 2024 - December 2024

- Developed dynamic, responsive user interfaces with JavaScript and React.
- Assisted in scalable web app development using Node.js and Java.
- Conducted unit testing and supported CI pipelines to ensure software quality.

Web Development Intern, Younity Data Analyst Intern, RINEX Marketing Intern, edernity

Freelance Development and AIML Projects

Jan 2024 - March 2024

Jan 2022 - Present

#### POSITION OF RESPONSIBILITIES

# Association for Computing Machinery, ACM USS

Video Lead and Executive member Nov 2022 - Present Managed team, created promotional materials, and organized successful events, showcasing strong design, creativity and leadership skills.

## ALCOM- Alumni Committee USS

Dec 2022 - Nov 2023

Event Management and Graphics designing: Manages various talk shows, alumni meet and other events...Used canva and Adobe Illustrator to make presentation, posters and social media posts

#### **Techspace**

Graphics Designer

Jan 2023 - Nov 2023

Designing: Created 30+ posts for the club Techspace which has around 700 members...promoted and successfully handled some events

# **Training and Placement Cell**

Placement Coordinator

Jan 2023 - Feb 2024

Managed a student database with academic records, resumes, contacts, and career preferences, supporting resume preparation, interview practice, and career guidance for holistic professional growth.

#### Harita - Environmental Society of USS

Nov 2022 - Mar 2024 Graphics Lead and Designer Led graphics team for Nature Club, creating 20+ posts and news-shorts. Promoted events like tree plantations, bird watching, wildlife talks, and nature walks.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- CyberSecurity Foundation Professional Certificate-CSFPC
- Participated in Girl Script Summer of Code 2023
- Participated in Girl Script Summer of Code 2024
- Several techstack certifications from letsupgrade
- Web Development Bootcamp Udemy (Issued: August 2022)
- Advanced OfficeSuite Certification Microsoft (Issued: Apr2023)
- Several work simulations from job forage

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Piston Exclusives**

Spearheaded brand creation, product design, and market positioning, catering to automotive enthusiasts with unique, high-quality apparel. Successfully built a niche brand recognized for its innovative approach to blending fashion with automotive culture.

#### withU247 - Mental Health App:

• The WithU247 Mental Health App is a comprehensive platform designed to support users in managing their mental well-being Tech: React Native, Node. js, Mongo DB, Firebase Authentication, AWS, Git and Git Hub

# AttendUS - A Web based Attendance App:

A Web based attendance monitoring solution which will give overall summary of a students attendance along with proper subject wise analysis. Tech: HTML, CSS, DB

#### Making Several AI/ML projects